어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!
여행을 계속하던 무사시는, 공산에서 이시마츠 유령하고 만나, 같이 죽자는 부탁을 듣게 되었다.
During his trip, Musashi met Ishimatsu's ghost in Osorezan and were asked to die together.
그렇지만 그건 오니히메의 함정이었다.
But that was a trap of Onihime.
그러나 무사시의 회오리권 앞에서 그 야망은 무너지고 말았다.
But in front of Musashi's Tornado, that ambition has been collapsed.
바다는 무섭네
오니고로시이오
The Sea is Scary
It's Onigoroshi
구름 한 점 없이 갠 푸른 하늘.
A clean blue sky without a single cloud.
마음도 갠 무사시 일행은 발걸음 가볍게 마음도 가볍게 홋카이도로 가고 있었다.
Musashi and others were heading to Hokkaido lightfootedly and lightheartedly.
어딜 봐도 바다뿐이야! 넓고 푸르고 바닷바람이 정말 좋아!
No matter which way I look at, I can only see the sea! It's wide, it's blue, and I like the salty see breeze!
큰 그림 위에 약간의 파도가. 센히메 님, 멀미하지 않도록 주의하세요.
It's as if some waves are on a big blue canvas. Senhime, please watch out for seasickness.
괜찮아, 괜찮아! 난 탈 것 잘 타!
It's alright, don't worry! I have no problems riding things.
그건 그렇지만, 저기 하나 탈 것 잘 못 타는 녀석이...
That's true, but you can see someone who can't over there...
뭐? 센히메 일행이 홋카이도로 가고 있다고?
What? Senhime and her subordinates are heading to Hokkaido?
예. 방금 들어온 정보입니다.
Yessir. It is a fresh information.
네 이놈, 센히메. 홋카이도로 건너가서 내 위대한 야망을 방해할 생각을...
That cursed Senhime... Trying to interrupt my great plan in Hokkaido?
카라쿠리 부엉이여, 오니고로시에게 알려라.
Karakuri Owl, let Onigoroshi know about this.
저기 보이는 저게 홋카이도?
Is that Hokkaido over there?
오, 겨우 보이는구나.
Finally. We're almost there.
잘 됐소... 나, 이대로 이 배에 계속 타고 있으면 머리가 흐늘흐늘 녹아내리오...
That's a relief-dasu... My head was getting limp ever since I got onto this ship-dasu...
뭘까, 저거?
I wonder what that is.
물고기는 아닌 것 같습니다만...
It surely does not look like a fish...
무슨 일이오?
What's wrong-dasu?
카라쿠리 상어가 공격해 온다!
Karakuri Shark is coming to attack!
카라쿠리 상어?
Karakuri Shark?
이대로는 침몰하겠어!
We're going down at this rate!
이걸 어째?!
What should we do?!
나, 수영 못 하오...
I don't know how to swim-dasu...
어딘가 구명 보트가 있다면...
If there's a lifeboat somewhere...
어?
Huh?
오니고로시
Onigoroshi
(Oni[g/k]oroshi: lit. Demon Slayer in Shōgi, an eastern chess)
오, 오니고로시다!
I- it's Onigoroshi!
오니고로시?
Onigoroshi?
모두! 돈이나 보물을 다 집어와라!
Everyone! Go take all the money and treasures!
예!
Yessir!
무사시!
Musashi!
알고 있소!
Got it-dasu!
다들! 돈이 될만한 건 하나도 빼먹지 말고 챙겨라!
Everyone! Take whatever that will make money!
도망쳐!
Run away!
누구냐!
Who are you?!
너 같은 해적 주제가 내 이름을 묻다니 주제를 넘는구나!
A pirate like you asking me my name is impertinent!
건방진 꼬맹이가. 바닷바닥으로 가라앉혀 주겠다!
You are one cocky kiddo! I'll make you sink to the very grounds of the sea!
코지로!
Kojirō!
젠장!
Damn!
배가 가라앉기 전에 다 챙겨라!
Take everything before the ship sinks!
우리, 어떻게 되는 걸까, 이대로 가라앉아 버린다면...
What will happen to us if we sink like this?
맡겨만 주시오. 내가 센짱을 지켜드리겠소!
Just leave it to me-dasu. I will protect Sen-chan-dasu!
쓸데없는 배려구만...
That was one useless help...
코지로는 괜찮을까.
I wonder if Kojirō's okay...
센짱, 빨리 도망치시오!
Sen-chan, hurry up and move-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
서두르시오!
Hurry up-dasu!
미안해!
I'm sorry!
다들 퇴각이다!
We're moving out!
무사시!
Musashi!
코지로! 어디!
Kojirō! Where are you?!
누, 누구야, 내 엉덩이에 붙은 게...
W- who's touching my hip?
무사시!
Musashi!
무사시...
Musashi...
어?
Huh?
참 답도 없는 놈이군.
What should I do with him...
나, 산골에서 자라서 바다에서 수영해 본 적 없소...
I was born in mountains, and because of that, I never swam in sea...
강이라면 조금 수영할 수는 있소만...
I can swim in river for a little-dasu, though...
칠칠치 못한 놈이군. 무예가라는 놈이 검술을 우아하게 하지 못할지라도,
How undisciplined are you! A martial artist may not be skillful in swordsmanship, but...
공수!
Karate!
유도!
Judo!
야구!
Baseball!
스케이트!
Skating!
수판!
Abacus!
따위를 익히는 건 최저 조건이지.
are the least one has to do.
게다가 나는 수영 3급의 실력도 있지.
Moreover, I have swimming skills of rank 3.
흥! 나도 수판 정도는 할 수 있소!
Hmph! I can at least use abacus-dasu!
Yeah, sure! Try calculating this in your head: someone has 159 yen, 257 yen...
그러셔? 그럼 암산해 봐! 누가 159엔이 있고, 257엔이 있고...
아, 시끄러워시끄러워시꺼시꺼시꺼!
Shutupshutupshutupshutupshutup!
암산 따위 하고 있을 때냐!
Did you really think now is the perfect time do mental figuring?!
이건, 센히메 님, 코지로라는 자가 꼴사나운 모습을 보여드리고 말았습니다...
Senhime, somebody named Kojirō just did an unsightly act...
할복하쇼, 할복!
Disembowel yourself-dasu! Go commit suicide!
뭐?!
What the hell?
아, 저기!
Hey, over there!
저기, 저기 봐봐!
Look! Look over there!
오! 배이오!
It's a ship-dasu!
자, 모두! 내 배에 타!
Everyone! Get on my ship!
네!
Yes!
오, 카라쿠리 상어인가. 잘 했다. 칭찬해 주지.
Is it you, Karakuri Shark? Good job. I applaudyou for that.
넌 분명... 오랜만에 한조 님께서 지령이 왔구나.
You must be... Finally, an order from Lord Hanzo.
겨우 마의 손에서 벗어난 센히메와 그 일행이지만, 재난이 끝나자마자 또 바로 재난.
Senhime and others just escaped from the evil hands, but another disaster was again waiting for them.
어떻소, 저 수줍어진 센짱 얼굴? 저거 분명 그것이오?
What do you think about her shying face-dasu? Does it mean that-dasu?
지금까지 없던 뜨거운 눈빛. 분명 저 사내에게 마음이 불타고 있는 거야.
Her hot eyesight is never seen before. Her spirit is burning down in front of that guy.
역시이오...
As I thought-dasu...
일단은 더 모습을 보고 있자.
Let's see how it goes for now.
저...
Um...
뭐야?
What is it?
이름 물어도 괜찮을지...
Can I ask your name?
난 다이스케야.
I am Daisuke.
나, 센이야. 잘 부탁해.
I am Sen. Looking forwards together...
상어가 있었지?
There was a shark, right?
어?
Huh?
카라쿠리 상어 말야.
Karakuri Shark, you know.
어, 있었어.
Uh, yeah, there was.
너, 카라쿠리 상어를 알고 있나?
Do you know Karakuri Shark?
난 그 카라쿠리 상어를 쫒고 있어.
I am chasing that Karakuri Shark.
카라쿠리 상어이오?
Karakuri Shark, you say-dasu?
그래.
Right.
왜야?
Why is that?
녀석은 해적 오니고로시가 쓰는 미운 놈이야.
It is a detestable guy that the pirate Onigoroshi uses.
내 아버지를 죽였어.
It killed my dad.
당신 아버지를?
Your dad?
아빠는 솜씨 좋은 어부였어. 그런데 그 놈에게 공격받던 어선을 도우려고 했더니...
My dad was a skillful fisher. But when he tried to help the ship being attacked by that...
아빠!
Dad!
그랬구나. 다이스케 씨 아버지에게 그런 일이 있었다니.
I see. That was a terrible thing to happen to your dad...
그 놈을 쓰러뜨려서 아빠 원수를 갚을 거야.
I will have revenge for my dad, by taking that down.
아버지의 원수를 갚고 싶다는 기분은 잘 알겠다. 그렇지만 상대는 거대하고 사나운 카라쿠리다.
I understand your will to have revenge for your father well. But your opponent is a huge and fierce Karakuri.
그 몸에 혹 상처가 난다면, 아버지가 슬퍼하실 것이다.
If you get hurt, your dad will be sad.
그만해. 그런 식으로 말하지 마.
Stop. Don't talk like that.
다이스케 씨는 지지 않을 거야. 절대 안 죽을 거야. 그렇지?
Mr. Daisuke will not lose. He will never die. Right?
물론. 난 죽지 않아. 카라쿠리 상어를 쓰러뜨릴 때까지는.
Of course. I will not die. At least until I take that Karakuri Shark down.
멋져... 점점 황홀해져!
So cool... I'm getting mesmerized!
무사시! 코지로! 우리도 도울 거야!
Musashi! Kojirō! We will help too!
도, 돕다니...
H- help...?
나, 또 빠지면...
If I get drowned again...
그럼 수영을 배워!
Then learn how to swim!
잠시 기다려 주세요. 아무리 명령이라 하더라도, 제너럴 이에야스에게서 일을 받은 이 코지로,
Please wait. Even if it's an order, I, Kojirō, got my job from General Ieyasu,
센히메 님을 상어 퇴치 따위의 위험한 일에 말려들게 할 수는 없습니다!
and I cannot let you be dragged into a dangerous job like shark extermination!
어, 뭐야, 코지로? 내가 평생 결혼 못 해도 된단 거야?
Oh, what did you say, Kojirō? Are you saying that you're fine with me not being able to marry for the rest of my life?
그런 뜻이 아닙니다.
That's not what I meant.
그럼 내 말 들어줄 거지?
Then will you do as I said?
예...
Okay...
그래서 수영 못 하는 무사시, 또 가라앉는가! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Does this mean Musashi, who can't swim, will have to drown again? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
다이스케의 복수를 힘을 빌려주기로 한 센히메는 마츠마이 성의 성주에게 협력을 부탁했다.
Senhime has decided to help with Daisuke's revenge, and she asked for a help to the feudal lord of Matsumai [?] castle.
그리고 무사시는 그 동안 코지로에게 훈련을 받고 있었다.
And while then, Kojirō was giving Musashi a training.
무사시, 똑바로 해라! 똑바로!
Musashi! Do it properly! Learn!
하나! 둘! 하나! 둘! 하나! 둘! 하나! 둘! 하나! 둘! 하나! 둘! 하나! 둘!
One! Two! One! Two! One! Two! One! Two! One! Two!
코지로, 나 벌써 힘드오...
Kojirō, I'm already tired-dasu...
우는 소리 하지 마라! 노력이다! 근성이다! 스파르타다!
Don't be a crybaby! Efforts! Guts! Spartan!
무슨...
The heck...
괴롭소...
That was painful-dasu...
근데, 무사시, 강에선 수영 잘만 하면서 왜 바다에서는 수영 못 하냐?
By the way, Musashi, why can't you swim in seas, when you can in rivers?
그, 그게 말이오, 좀 부끄럽소...
T- that is-dasu... a bit embarrassing-dasu...
바닷물은 소금물이오.
Seawater is saltwater-dasu, right?
그렇지.
Yeah.
그게, 단고나 만두 단 건 좋아하는데, 짠 건 잘 못 먹소.
That is, I like sweet dangos and dumplings, but not the salty ones-dasu.
어?
What?
멍청한 자식.
Moron.
다이스케 씨!
Mr. Daisuke!
안 늦어서 다행이야!
I wasn't late, after all!
지금 막 퇴치하려 가려던 참이야.
I was about to go exterminate the shark.
다이스케 씨에게 줄 게 있어.
I have something to give to you.
어? 나한테 줄 거?
What? Something for me?
슬슬 올 거야.
It'll be here soon.
봐봐!
Look!
왔어!
It's here!
오다니, 저 배?
You mean, that ship?
센짱!
Sen-chan!
저, 저 배를 나한테...
T- that ship, for me...
그래. 저걸로 아버지 원수 꽉 갚아줘!
Yeah. Have revenge for your father with that!
저 누더기 배로?
With that scrap ship?!
보이기엔 그렇게 보일지 몰라도, 비밀의 무기가 잔뜩 달려 있어!
It does look so, but it is full of secret weapons!
그렇구나! 센짱, 고마워! 감사해!
I see! Thank you so much, Sen-chan!
상어하고 만날 수 있으려나...
I wonder if we can meet that Shark well...
걱정할 필요 없어! 이렇게 짐을 많이 싣고 있으니 그 놈, 분명 나타날 거야.
No need to worry! We're having this much load. It is bound to appear.
카라쿠리 상어다!
Karakuri Shark!
나타났군, 카라쿠리 상어! 오늘이야말로 아버지의 원수를 갚아 주겠다!
You've finally appeared, Karakuri Shark! I will have the revenge for my dad today!
당하겠어!
It's gonna get us!
이, 이건...
N- no way!
-대, 대단해!
-그치? 내가 특별히 부탁했어!
-A- awesome!
-Yeah, it is! I specially asked for this!
이 배라면 카라쿠리 상어가 악물고 덤벼도 괜찮다.
On this ship, we'll be alright even if that Karakuri Shark decides to do a ramming attack.
그렇소!
That's right-dasu!
저건 분명 센히메.
That must be Senhime.
이걸로 한조 님께서 보상을 잔뜩 받아갈 수 있겠지.
Lord Hanzo will award me a lot of goods.
오니고로시다!
Onigoroshi!
오니고로시는 나하고 무사시가 상대하겠다. 넌 카라쿠리 상어를 퇴치해서 아버지의 원수를 갚아라.
Musashi and I will face Onigoroshi. You will exterminate that Karakuri Shark and have revenge for your father.
알았어.
Got it.
다이스케 씨... 힘내...
Mr. Daisuke... You can do this...
다이스케 씨...
Mr. Daisuke...
좋아, 무사시! 해적 놈들을 놀래키자!
Alright! Musashi, let's scare those pirates!
좋소!
Right-dasu!
이 꼬맹이들이! 용서할 수 없다! 내 무서움을 단단히 알려주겠다!
Those brats! Unforgivable! I will show my horror!
다이스케 씨!
Mr. Daisuke!
놀랐냐, 꼬맹아!
Bet you were scared, you brat!
놀랐소...
I was scared-dasu...
그래도 나는 지지 않소! 자, 덤벼들어 보시오, 오니기리코로리(주먹밥 데구르르)!
But I will not lose-dasu! You may come attack-dasu, Onigiri-korori(Rolling rice ball)!
뭐, 뭐야? 오니기리코로리가 아니라 오니고로시다!
W- what?! It's not Onigirikorori! It's Onigoroshi!
어? 오니코로리(도깨비 데구르르)?
What? Onikorori(Rolling monster)?
오니고로시다!
It's Onigoroshi!
잘 안 들리오! 오니고로(도깨비 깡패)이오?
I can't hear you-dasu! Is it Onigoro(Monster hooligan)?
에이, 웃길 생각 마라!
You think you're clever, eh?!
기다려라, 꼬맹아!
Wait right there, you brat!
자, 꼬맹아! 네 앞길은 지옥이다!
Now, a hell is waiting in front of you brat!
흥이다! 지옥에 가는건 당신이오! 내가 가는 곳은 단고집이오!
That's hmph for you! You're the one to go to the hell-dasu! I'm going to dango store-dasu!
지옥의 단고집에나 가라!
Then go to the dango store in hell!
이대로는 안 되겠어. 어떻게든 해야...
This isn't working. I must do something...
다이스케 씨!
Mr. Daisuke!
부탁이야! 창을 던져 줘!
Please! Throw a spear to here!
알았어!
Got it!
던질게, 다이스케 씨!
I'm throwing this, Mr. Daisuke!
좋아!
Right!
이랴!
Here!
조심해! 날 죽일 셈이냐!
Watch out! You almost got me!
미, 미안해!
I- I'm sorry!
그래도, 그렇게 말할 것까지는 없었는데...
But you didn't have to talk harshly...
눈을 노리자. 눈을.
Aim for its eyes.
무사시! 여긴 다 해결됐어!
Musashi! I'm done down here!
기다려 주시오! 여기도 오니코로리를 막 잡으려던 참이오!
Just a moment-dasu! I'm about to get Onikorori soon-dasu!
입 한번 잘 놀리는군, 이 무사쿠루시(누추하다)!
What a big mouth you have, you Musakurushii(filthy)!
무사쿠루시 아니오! 무사시이오! 이 오니상고로치!
It's not Musakurushii, you Onisangorochi!
오니고로시다!
It's Onigoroshi!
쟤들 뭐하냐?
What's wrong with them?
각오나 해라!
Just prepare yourself!
각오 안 하오!
I don't prepare-dasu!
당황하지 마라, 무사시. 하나, 둘, 하나, 둘. 이 리듬이다.
Do not be surprised, Musashi. One, two, one, two. You know the rhythm.
그렇소. 하나, 둘, 하나, 둘이오. 소금물이라도 감안하오.
That's right-dasu. One, two, one, two-dasu. Even in saltwater I can do this-dasu.
하나, 둘, 하나, 둘, 하나, 둘, 하나, 둘...
One, two, one, two, one, two, one, two...
아, 쑥쑥 잘 지나가지오! 큰 강에서 수영하던 것처럼 대강 하니 되오. 역시 난 농담 잘 하오.
I'm swimming smoothly-dasu! Swimming in ri-ver isn't re-ally different here-dasu. Also, I'm good at jokes-dasu.
다이스케 씨!
Mr. Daisuke!
다이스케 씨, 괜찮소?
Mr. Daisuke, are you alright-dasu?
괜찮아! 이 놈을 잡아 아빠의 원수를 갚기 전까진 죽을 수 없어!
I'm alright! I can't die until I have revenge for my dad!
조, 조심해!
W- watch out!
다이스케 씨, 위험하오! 빨리 도망치시오!
Mr. Daisuke, it's dangerous here-dasu! Let's escape-dasu!
아니, 난 도망치지 않아! 너 혼자서 도망쳐!
No, I won't run away! You can escape by yourself!
대체 무슨 소리를...
That's nonsense!
도망치시오!
We're running away-dasu!
고마워. 네 덕분에 아빠 원수를 갚을 수 있었어.
Thank you. I could have revenge for my dad thanks to you.
어떻게 보답해야 할지...
I don't know how to repay this...
아냐, 괜찮아. 다이스케 씨가 기뻐한다면 난 행복해.
No, you don't need to do anything. I'm happy if you're happy.
난 다시 어부 일을 해야겠어.
I will become a fisher again.
나, 물고기 정말 좋아해! 매일 먹을 수 있어.
I like eating fishes really much! I can eat them every day.
센짱, 저런 소리를 하오.
Sen-chan is saying that-dasu...
쉿!
Shh!
다이스케 씨!
Mr. Daisuke!
아, 오사키!
Hey, Osaki!
그럼 돌아갈게!
Then I'll be going!
어...
Yeah...
저런, 이럴 것 같았소.
I knew this was coming-dasu.
그러게...
Agreed...
센짱! 나 수영할 수 있게 됐소!
Sen-chan! I can swim now-dasu!
이야, 무사시 참 잘 했어요!
Wow, Musashi did a great job!
그렇네. 내가 좋아하게 된 사람 중에 애인이 될 사람이 한둘은 있겠지?
Yeah. There will be at least one or two people I like that actually will become my lover, right?
그렇소! 힘내고 삿포로 라면이나 먹으러 가오!
That's right-dasu! Don't feel bad, and let's go eat some Sapporo ramen-dasu!
그렇네! 나물 잔뜩으로!
Right! With a lot of bean sprouts!
나물이오!
Bean sprouts-dasu!
같이 가요!
Wait for us!
북쪽의 바다에서 펴 덧없이 진 사랑의 꽃. 그렇지만 강하고 밝게 여행을 계속하는 센히메의 가슴 한편. 과연 누가 알아줄 것인가.
Bloomed at a northern sea, and evanescently fell is a flower of love.
But just like the inside Senhime's heart, she kept traveling strongly and brightly. Who will understand her at last?
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't worry too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep going! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
홋카이도에 가던 우리는 오랜만에 바이켄 형제하고 만났소.
We met Baiken brothers during our way to Hokkaido again-dasu.
맛있는 라면을 먹고, 몸을 녹이고, 따끈따끈도 잠시, 수상한 닌자 군단에 습격당하는 임시 주거지를 돕기 위해,
We ate great ramens, bask ourselves and it was all warm, but soon,
to help the temporary dwelling being attacked by suspicious ninja force,
가도 가도 새하얀 광야를 포장마차에 타 주파하오!
we run over a vast plain of limitless white on a covered wagon!
다음 이야기! 홋카이웨스턴의 사투이오
Next story! Desperate Struggle in Hokkai-Western
질풍노도의 무사시 특급우편이오!
It's a stormy Musashi Priority Mail Express-dasu!
다음 이야기
홋카이웨스턴의 사투이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Desperate Struggle
in Hokkai-Western
Look forwards for it!